

Alvin E. Garin

Muntinlupa city, Philippines garinalvin.e@gmail.com +63 932 124 2045

Summary

Experienced professional with over 5 years of experience in the manufacturing industry, with expertise in manufacturing data analysis and machine line support function. Has in-depth knowledge in MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, basic python programming and SQL. Strong verbal and written communication skills.

Career history

Probe Engineer at Allegro Microsystems Philippines Inc.

May 2020 - Jun 2023 (3 years 2 months)

- Performs data gathering and analysis of production status and line issues.
- Generates daily, weekly and monthly reports.
- Generate gage report and review data for new hardware and system spares.
- Check and help update process documents.
- Update and/or correct process records
- Provide line sustaining support
- Check possible program related issues
- Interacts with other group to resolve line issues
- Line Improvement projects
- Perform repairs of Eagle test system and TEL Prober
- Debug device to system limitations
- Check test programs for possible improvements for system compatibility issues.

Probe Sustaining Technician at Allegro Microsystems Philippines Inc.

Oct 2017 - May 2020 (2 years 8 months)

- maintains machine in running good condition.
- analyses test data
- validates test rejects
- coordinates with engineers the gathered test data

Apprentice Engineer at Amkor Technology Phils. Inc.

Feb 2017 - Jul 2017 (6 months)

- 5 months training for NC2 certification on assembly of semiconductor products

Skills

Eagle Test System Debugging, hardware debugging, Eagle Test system program debugging,

Basic python programming, galaxy examinator, o+ portal app, office apps such as Microsoft Excel,

PowerPoint and Word, Data Analysis, PostgreSQL using pgAdmin, PowerBI basics.

Hardworking, Fast learner, attention to detail, ability to work independently, willingness to learn, adaptability.

Languages

English, Filipino

Education

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering from Colegio de Dagupan

Finished 2016

Certifications

Python (Basic) Programming

Issued by Hacker Rank

Mar 2023 - Current

- Certification of clearing the assessment for the skill Python (Basic)
- Certification link: https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/9985072cd1cf

CS50P - Introduction to Python Programming Course

Issued by Harvard University

Oct 2023 - Current

- Certification on completion of CS50's Introduction to Programming With Python, including nine problem sets and one final project.
- cert link: https://cs50.harvard.edu/certificates/5b3f6d3e-46d2-4ca4-a170-5859ffea6d38